[
    {
        "question" : "Consider the following differences between RBCs and WBCs: 1.While RBCs do not have nucleus, WBCs have nucleus in them2.Life span of RBCs is higher than that of WBCs. Which of the above statements is/are correct?",
        "a" : "1 Only",
        "b" : "2 Only",
        "c" : "Both 1 & 2",
        "d" : "Neither 1 nor 2",
        "answer" : "c"
    },

    {
        "question" : "When the white light is incident on the refracting face of the prism: 1.red waves undergo least deviation 2.waves with longer wavelength deviate lesser 3.the phenomenon of differential deviation of rays is called dispersion Which among the above statements is / are correct?",
        "a" : " Only 1",
        "b" : "Only 1 & 2",
        "c" : "Only 2 & 3",
        "d" : "Only 1 & 3",
        "answer" : "d"
    },    
    
    {
        "question" : "The phenomenon due to which animal sweat to reduce temperature and change electrolyte concentration is called:",
        "a" : "Homeorhesis",
        "b" : "Homeostasis",
        "c" : "Apoptosis",
        "d" : "Necrobiosis",
        "answer" : "b"
    },    
    
    {
        "question" : "Which one of the following is NOT the feature of tribal religion?",
        "a" : "magic plays big role in it",
        "b" : "people have a full faith in supernatural power",
        "c" : "there is no faith in animism",
        "d" : "people have faith in animatism",
        "answer" : "c"
    },

    {
        "question" : "Among the Bhil and Toda tribes common type of marriage is:",
        "a" : "endogamy",
        "b" : "exogamy",
        "c" : "both endogamy and exogamy",
        "d" : "neither endogamy nor exogamy",
        "answer" : "a"
    },

    {
        "question" : "Among the Tujan and Kurumb common type of family prevailing is:",
        "a" : "polyandry",
        "b" : "polygamy",
        "c" : "monogamy",
        "d" : "none of the above",
        "answer" : "a"
    },    
    
    {
        "question" : "An intelligent and educated temple priest has an importance in the village community. To what do you attribute his role and status?",
        "a" : "Being an educated man, he is friend, philosopher and guide",
        "b" : "Besides performing his priestly functions, he is astrologer, and conductor of the community prayer",
        "c" : "He is the judge of good and bad",
        "d" : " All of the above",
        "answer" : "d"
    },    
    
    {
        "question" : "Mark out the incorrect statement-",
        "a" : "Urbanites are socially poor in midst of plenty",
        "b" : "Urban contacts are segmental",
        "c" : "Urbanities come into primary contact with each other",
        "d" : "Many urbanites live in social vacuum",
        "answer" : "c"
    },

    {
        "question" : "________ is more rampant in a city life.",
        "a" : "Social mobility",
        "b" : "Migration",
        "c" : "Religious grouping",
        "d" : "Jajmani system",
        "answer" : "a"
    },

    {
        "question" : "Who can be labelled as a historical sociologist?",
        "a" : "Pareto",
        "b" : "Karl Marx",
        "c" : "Max Weber",
        "d" : "Lewis Coscer",
        "answer" : "c"
    }


]